Ghulaam Ellahi

11 Bell Drive, B8 3BG

E - Mail: gm.ellahi@gmail.com

Personal Profile

I am a full - time wheelchair user and am a recent Computer Games Technology graduate with a passion for programming. My strengths are in games programming, but I also have experience with web development and can adapt myself to learn various other programming languages. Furthermore, I have great communication and teamworking skills for when collaborating with different people. I enjoy attending game jams and hackathons, as it helps to enhance my programming and problem - solving skills as well as my communication skills.

Education

Birmingham City University (2015 – 2018)

BSc (Hons) Computer Games Technology - 2:1

Joseph Chamberlain Sixth Form College (2013 – 2015)

BTEC Level 3 ICT (National Extended Diploma) - D*D*D*

Hall Green Secondary School (2008 – 2013)

• 10 GCSEs - A to C grade

Employment and Work Experience

Student Ambassador (Oct 2017 - June 2018)

I worked as a student ambassador on open and applicant visit days at Birmingham City University, in order to help prospective students by providing more in - depth information about the course I studied at university, so that they can decide whether or not the course is right for them.

Marketing Assistant (June 2012 - July 2012)

I conducted work experience with an ICT marketing firm called "Tomorrow People" for two weeks and through this gained vital ICT and marketing skills. In addition, I have learned about the inbound marketing and content marketing processes as well as how the processes affect Tomorrow People as an overall business.

Final Year Project

For my final year project, I developed an Augmented Reality application that educates people about the planets of the solar system. This was to find out whether or not Augmented Reality supports a range of learning styles. Furthermore, I also collaborated with the Birmingham Science Museum (Thinktank) and had set up an exhibition outside the planetarium at the museum, to promote the museum whilst gaining extra feedback on the application for my dissertation.

Technical Skills

• Games Development - Unity, Visual Studio, Irrlicht and DirectX ...

General Programming - C#, C++ and Python ...

Web Development - HTML and CSS

Modern Technologies - VR, AR and MR

• Application Development - XCode and Android Studio

Achievements

Joseph Chamberlain Sixth Form College - Certificate of Commendation

• I achieved an award from my college in recognition of my achievement.

Second Team Player of the Year

 I received an award for being the player of the year in the second team, when I used to play for the Aston Villa Rockets wheelchair football team. In addition, I also received various other medals whilst playing for the football team.

Contact

- Email gm.ellahi@gmail.com
- Website (Portfolio) ghully007.github.io
- LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/ghulaam-ellahi-307a0613a/

References

• References available upon request.